This is a story of boy meets girl.
这是一个男孩遇见女孩的故事
This belief stemmed from early exposure to sad British pop music...
这个想法来自于早期接触的悲伤英国流行音乐...
The girl, Summer Finn of Shinnecock, Michigan did not share this belief.
女主角莎莫 芬恩  来自密歇根州的辛尼克却不这么想
Since the disintegration of her parents marriage, she'd only loved two things.
自从她父母的婚姻破裂之后她只爱两样东西
The first was her long dark hair.
第一是她乌黑的长发
The second was how easily she could cut it off...and feel nothing.
而第二是她可以轻易的把它剪掉...却毫不在意
Tom meets Summer on January 8.
汤姆 在一月八号那天遇见了 莎莫
He knows almost immediately she's who he's been searching for.
他在那一刻突然明白了 莎莫 就是他要找的那个人
This is a story of boy meets girl.
这是个男孩遇见女孩的故事
But you should know up front this is not a love story.
但我要先告诉你这不是个爱情故事
We didn't know who else to call.
我们不知道还能打给谁
It's Amanda Heller all over again.
阿曼达 海勒事件重演
You did the right thing.
你做的很对
Now where is he?
他现在在哪？
Rachel, what are you doing here?
瑞切尔 你怎么在这儿？
First put down the plate.
首先 把碟子放下
Drink this.
喝了它
Just start from the beginning, and tell us what happened.
就从开始讲告诉我们出什么事了
Things were going so well.
一切都进展得很好
I think we should stop seeing each other.
我认为我们不应该再见面了
I mean, is this normal?
我的意思是 这正常吗？
Maybe she was just in a bad mood.
可能她只是心情不好
Yeah, maybe like a...a hormonal thing.
对，可能只是... 激素什么的
More than you Tom. Then what happened?
比你知道得多 汤姆   之后什么发生了？
This can't come as a total surprise to you.
你不会觉得太意外吧
Let's eat, and we'll talk about it later.
我们吃吧  过会再聊
I'm really glad we did this.
真高兴我们做了这些
I love these pancakes.
我喜欢这儿的薄饼
What?
什么？
Tom, you're still my best friend!
汤姆  你还是我的最好的朋友！
Jesus.  You've broken up with girls before.
上帝   你以前甩过别的女孩
Yes.
对
And girls have broken up with you before.
以前也有女孩甩过你
This is different. Why?
这不一样   为什么？
Cause it's Summer.
因为是 Summer
So you'll...you'll meet somebody new.
所以你要... 你要再找一个
I think it's kind of like how they say... Ur...
就像俗话说... 呃...
There's plenty of other fish in the sea.
海里有很多鱼
No.  They say that...
不对 俗话是这么说的 ......
Well, they're lying.
好吧  他们在说谎
I don't want to get over her.
我不想忘了她
I want to get her back.
我想让她回来
Maybe playing it safe is the wrong approach.
可能求稳是错误的方式
The nuclear family is dead
核心家庭垮了
and we need a new holiday that recognizes that.
我们需要一个新的假日来认识这
May 21 st.
5月21号
Other Mother's Day.
另一个母亲节
Thank you.
谢谢
I'd say we've got some potential here. What do you think, Hansen?
我觉得很有市场 汉森 你怎么看？
Could you write up some prototypes for these?
你能详细地说一下吗？
Mr. Vance, there's a telephone call for you on line three.
Vance 先生  三线有电话找你
Oh. Thank you.  Everyone, this is Summer, my new assistant.
哦  谢谢  各位  这是莎莫 我的新助理
Michigan. Right. Michigan. Right.
密歇根  对 密歇根
Everyone, Summer.
各位 这是 莎莫
It's nice to meet you all.
见到各位很荣幸
There's only two kinds of people in the world.
世界上只有两种人
Summer Finn was a woman.
莎莫是个女人
Height, average. Weight, average.
身高  平均数  体重  平均数
Shoe size, slightly above average.
鞋码 比平均数略小
To wit, in 1998,Summer quoted a song by the Scottish band Belle and Sebastian...in her high school yearbook.
比如  在1998年 莎莫 在她的高中毕业纪念册上引用了苏格兰贝儿与塞巴斯乐团的一首歌
This spike in Michigan sales of their album "The Boy with the Arab Strap" continues to puzzle industry analysts.
让他们的唱片 " 系着阿拉伯皮带的男孩 "在密歇根大卖一直困扰着产业分析家
Summer's employment at the Daily Freeze during her sophomore year coincided with an inexplicable 212% increase in revenue.
莎莫大二的时候在冰淇淋店打工这家店的收益也莫名其妙的增加了 212%
Every apartment Summer rented was offered at an average rate of 9.2% below market value.
每次莎莫租房价格都比市场均价低 9.2%
And her round-trip commute to work averaged 18.4 double takes per day.
她上下班的路上平均每天让人回头 18.4 次
It was a rare quality, "Summer effect."
这是很稀有的现象 "莎莫效应 "
Rare, and yet something every post adolescent male has encountered at least once in their lives.
稀有   却是所有青春期的雄性动物遇到过的一生中至少一次
Dude, I hear she's a bitch.
嗨  我听说她是个婊子
Really?
是吗
Maybe she was just in a hurry.
可能她只是很忙
And maybe she's an uppity, "better than everyone" superskank.
也可能她是个高傲女   " 比所有人都优秀 " 真扯蛋
Damn. I know. She's pretty hot.
小子  我看到了  她很火辣
You know what? Screw her. I don't care.
你知道什么？ 随便她 跟我没关系
Smiths?
史密斯？
Hi.
嗨
I love the Smiths.
我喜欢史密斯
I said I love the Smiths.
我说   我喜欢史密斯的歌
You have... You have good taste in music.
你   嗯... 你品位不错
You like the Smiths? Yeah.
你喜欢史密斯？对
There you go. Have another piece.
这是你的 再来一块
Drinks?
要酒吗？
Arthur, did you get a piece? Thanks.
亚瑟   你有蛋糕吗？ 谢谢
Want one? Yeah.
来一杯？  好
Want one? Mmm.
来一杯？  嗯
Smiths fan. Yeah. Tom.
史密斯迷  哦  我是汤姆
It's not champagne. I don't know what it is. Sure.
不是香槟 我不知道是什么  好吧
So, how's it goin'?
最近怎么样？
Pretty good. You just moved here, right?
很好  你刚搬来吧？
And, uh, what brought you?
呃 ...... 什么把你招来了？
Boredom mostly.
各种烦人的事
Wanted to try something new and exciting. Mmm.
想找点新鲜事干  嗯
Well, clearly you've come to the right place.
很明显这里是个好选择
So, have you worked here long? About three or four years.
那  你会在这呆多久  三四年吧
Wow. You've...
哇  你...
always wanted to write greeting cards?
一直很喜欢写贺卡吗？
No, I don't even want to do it now.
不  我现在就不想
Well, you should do something else then.
那你应该做点别的
Yeah. I studied to be an architect, actually.
其实  我是学建筑的
You did? That's cool. What happened there?
是吗？  真棒  然后呢？
Well, um, I wrote this one.
好吧  我写了这个
It's a big seller. I meant as an architect.
很畅销   我是说建筑方面
I doubt it. Well,
我觉得不行  恩
you're a perfectly adequate greeting card writer.
你是个写贺卡的高手
They used to call me "Anal Girl".
他们以前叫我 " 肛门女 "
I was very neat and organized.
我以前有洁癖
Well, I should get back.
我该过去了
All right. See you later.
好吧   回见
I don't know, man. I think it's official.
我不知道  好吧  我认为这很正式
I'm in love with Summer. I love her smile.
我爱上莎莫了   我爱她的笑
I love her hair. I love her knees.
爱她的头发  爱她的膝盖
I love this heart-shaped birthmark she has on her neck.
爱她脖子上心型的胎记
I love the way she sometimes licks her lips before she talks.
爱她时不时说话前舔一下嘴唇
I love the sound of her laugh.
爱听她笑
I love the way she looks when she's sleeping.
爱她睡觉时的样子
I love how I hear this song every every time I think of her.
爱每次听到这首歌的时候就想起她
I love how she makes me feel.
爱她给我的感觉
Like anything's possible.
就像什么都有可能
This is not good.
这不是什么好事
She likes Magritte and Hopper.
她喜欢马格利特和霍普
We're so compatible, it's insane.
我们很合适  真疯狂
Red team wins! What do you mean?
红队胜！   你说什么？
No, but it could have been, in a world where good things happen to me.
没有 但是如果走运的话  还有可能
So, what happened?
那么 发生了什么？
How was your weekend?
周末过的怎么样
It was good.
棒极了
She basically said she spent the weekend having sex with some guy she met at the gym.
她的意思是说  她整个周末都在健身房和某个小子做爱
There's really nothing I can do about that.
我无能为力了
I gave her plenty of chances.
我给了她很多机会
I'm going to the supply room. Do you guys need anything?
我要去库房  你们谁要带点东西？
I think you know what I need.
我觉得你知道我要什么
Okay. Sure. No problem.
好的  没问题
I'm comfortable. I'm unhassled.
我很平静 很淡定
People don't realize this, but loneliness...
人们没发现  但寂寞...
Don't be stupid.
别傻了
Ah, I wasn't that bad.
呃 没那么糟吧
Dude, you threw up on the stage, you tried to fight the bartender...
哥们 你吐到台上 差点跟酒保打起来...
And you threatened to burn the place down.
你还威胁要烧了那家店
But I didn't burn the place down.
- 但我没有真的烧了它
What? The whole office is going.
什么? 所有办公室的人都要去
Hi. Hi.
嗨  嗨
They said you weren't coming.
他们说你不来了
That song is brilliant!
这歌太棒了
That's me. Come on up.
该我了  快上来
I didn't, uh... I didn't know you were gonna join us.
我不...呃... 我不知道你要加入我们
I wanted to sing "Born To Run," but they didn't have it.
我本来想唱 "生来奔波" 可他们没有
I love "Born To Run." Me too.
我喜欢 "生来奔波"   我也是
Tom's from New Jersey. Really?
汤姆是新泽西人  是吗？
Yeah. I grew up there. I lived there till I was 12.
恩  我在那长大  12岁才离开
I named my cat after Springsteen.
我的猫就姓斯普林斯丁
No kidding. what was his name?
别开玩笑了 它叫什么？
Bruce.
布鲁斯
So, do you have a boyfriend?
那么  你有男朋友吗？
No. Why not?
没有  为什么不找个？
You don't believe that a woman could enjoy being free and independent?
你不相信一个女人能享受自由独立？
Are you a lesbian?
你是女同？
No, I'm not a lesbian.
不 我不是
I just don't feel comfortable being anyone's girlfriend.
我只是感觉做谁的女朋友会不舒服
I don't actually feel comfortable being anyone's anything.
我不想是任何人的任何人
I don't know what you're talking about. Really?
我不知道你在说什么   是吗？
Nope.
不明白
Relationships are messy, and people's feelings get hurt.
关系太复杂  人们觉得受伤
Who needs it? We're young.
谁希望这样？  我们还年轻
We live in one of the most beautiful cities in the world.
我们住在这世上最漂亮的城市
Might as well have fun while we can and save the serious stuff for later.
为什么不开心点把那些严肃的问题先扔一边
Okay. But wait, what happens if you fall in love?
好  但等一下  如果你恋爱了怎么办？
What?
什么？
Well, you don't believe that, do you?
你不会相信那些吧？
It's love. It's not Santa Claus.
是爱  不是圣诞老人
Well, what does that word even mean?
好吧  那个字代表什么？
I've been in relationships, and I don't think I've ever seen it.
我有过那种关系  但我不觉得我见过
There's no such thing as love. It's a fantasy.
没爱情这回事  那是童话
Well, I think you're wrong.
我认为不对
what is it that I'm missing then?
我漏了什么？
I think you know it when you feel it.
当你感觉到爱的时候你就明白了
I guess we can just agree to disagree.
求同存异吧
Yeah.
好吧
I nominate Young werther here.
我推荐这位少年维特
I used to watch it every week. Oh. Yeah!
我以前每周都看  哦 对
It was the best show on TV. I know.
那是最好的电视节目  我知道
Knight Rider? And the theme song is really good.
霹雳游侠？ 主题曲太棒了
So good. This is gonna bother me for a week.
太棒了 我惦记了一周
Me too.
我也是
You're amazing.
你太棒了
He likes you. Okay.
他喜欢你  好了
He likes likes you! Good night, McKenzie.
他喜欢你！  晚安 肯德基
Why don't you just tell her, Tom? Yeah.
汤姆你为什么不告诉她？好了
What thing?
什么
Do you... like me?
你... 喜欢我吗？
Yeah.
对
Yeah, of course I like you.
对  当然 我喜欢你
As friends?
朋友那种？
Right. As friends.
对  朋友
Just as friends?
只是朋友那样？
Yes. Why?
对  怎么了？
Is that all right?
可以吗
Yeah. You and me. We should be friends. Mmm.
对  你和我  我们应该成为朋友   嗯
Okay. Good.
恩  好的
Well, I'm that way.
那么   我走这边
Okay. Well, good night. Good night.
好吧  晚安   晚安
Paul You were essentially stalking her!
保罗 你根本就是盯梢她！
Paul! Shh!
保罗！  闭嘴！
I'm Paul. Hi, Paul. Nice to meet you.
我是保罗  嗨 保罗  很高兴见到你
Well, I gotta go. I gotta do some.
好吧   我该走了  我还有些事
Thanks, Paul! See ya!
谢了  保罗！  回见！
He's, uh... you know, an old friend.
他... 呃 老朋友了
If you heard any of...
如果你听到...
Heard what? Nothing. You wanna go?
听到什么？  没什么  你要走了吗？
Yeah. I'm stalking.
对  我在盯梢
Our sink is broken.
我们的水池坏了
No, I don't think so.
不  算了吧
Home, sweet home.
家  温暖的家
Our place really is lovely, isn't it?
咱们家可真好  是吧？
Yes.
恩
The TV's not working.
电视坏了
Oh.
哦
Well, I'm famished.
好吧  我饿死了
Let's eat.
吃点东西去
Mmm. Smells delicious.
嗯 真好闻
Oh, honey, that's because it is delicious.
哦  亲爱的  它真的很好吃
I made it myself.
我自己做的
The sink's broken.
水池坏了
Well, that's okay, because...
没事  因为 ...
That's why we bought a home with two kitchens.
就是为什么  我们有两个厨房
You're so smart.
你真聪明
I'll race you to the bedroom.
看谁先到卧室
Darling, I don't know how to tell you this,
亲爱的  我怎么跟你说
but... there's a Chinese family in our bathroom.
可是... 那些中国人在咱们浴室
You're fun.
你真有趣
Thanks.
谢谢
Hey, um,
嗨  呃
I just wanna tell you that, um,
我想跟你说 嗯
Is that okay?
这样好吗？
Yeah.
没事
'Cause some people kind of freak out when they hear that.
大多数人听到这个都很崩溃
No, not me.
我不会
You sure?
真的吗？
Yeah. Like, casual. Right? Take it slow.
就像暧昧  对吧？  慢慢来
Right.
对
No pressure.
没压力
Can you, uh... Can you wait one second?
等等... 你能等一下吗？
Okay. Settle. She's just a girl.
冷静点  她只是个女孩
Just a girl.
只是个女孩
She wants to keep it casual,which is why she's in my bed right now.
她想保持暧昧，这就是为什么她现在在我床上
That's fine. That's great.
好吧  没事
Is this Solitaire?
这个是单人纸牌吗？
So, did you get her back yet or what?
那么，她回心转意了还是其他什么？
Working on it.
继续工作吧
Hey, maybe you should write a book. What?
嗨，也许你该写本书  什么？
Henry Miller said the best way to get over a woman...is to turn her into literature.
亨利·米勒说过  忘掉一个女人的最好方法...就是把她变成文学
Well, that guy had a lot more sex than me.
那他做的爱肯定比我多
Oh, this is it! This is it!
哇  就是这个！  就是这个！
So great to hear from you.
很高兴收到你的信
I can't this week, but maybe next?
但是这周不行  要不下周
I hope this means you're ready to be friends.
我希望这代表着  你已经准备好做朋友了
Your girl is losing it.
你的妞疯了
"octopus's Garden" is the best Beatles song ever recorded.
“章鱼花园” 是披头士发行的最好的歌
Come on. I love Ringo Starr!
别闹了  我喜欢 林戈·斯塔尔
No, no.
不  不
Ooh, this looks good.
哇  看起来不错
Gets really good reviews.
评价很高
You know what? That looks pretty doable.
你知道吗？   看起来太难以置信了
Put your hand there. Wait one second.
手放这  等一下
Okay. Three, two,  One.
好了  三 二 一
The street level isn't so exciting,
逛街可能没那么好玩
The guys who designed this, Walker and Eisen, are... two of my favorites.
这栋楼的设计师   沃克和艾森是...  我最喜欢的两个
This is my favorite spot. This is?
这是我最喜欢的地方  这吗？
This is your favorite spot?
这是你最喜欢的地方？
Right here.
就是这
How come?
怎么说？
Uh, I don't know. It's kind of hard to explain, I guess.
额 我不知道  很难解释 我猜
That's been there since 1911.
它 1911 年就在那了
It was built in 1904.
1904 年建成的
That?
那个？
That's a parking lot. Oh!
那个是停车场   噢！
There's a lot of beautiful stuff here too though...
还有很多漂亮的建筑  虽然...
I don't know. I just... wish people would notice it more.
我不知道...我只是... 我只是希望人们更多的注意到
If it were me, then, uh...
如果是我 ，那么，嗯...
If it were you what?
如果你什么？
I don't know. I think I'd... make them notice.
我不知道..我想我会...让人们注意到吧
How would you make them notice?
你怎么引起他们的注意？
I don't know. There's a lot of different stuff you could do.
我不知道  太多可以做的了
Show me.
给我看看
Please. I don't know anything about architecture.
拜托 我对建筑一点都不懂
You want me to draw you something? Yeah.
你想让我画出来？对
I don't have any paper. Well, use my arm.
我没纸  那么，用我的胳膊吧
Please, I need a tattoo.
求你了  我想要个纹身
Well, let's see your arm. That's the spirit.
那么，让我们看看你的胳膊 那就是灵感
Well, the buildings need to be integrated better
嗯 要把建筑描绘得更精确一些
You could maximize light capacity here.
可以把轮廓画大一些
It's kind of messy.
有点乱
That's okay.
没事
For here was Tom, in her world,a place few had been invited to see with their own eyes.
是汤姆进入了她的世界，一个很少人可以进入的世界
And here was Summer, wanting him there.
莎莫希望他进来
Him, no one else.
他 而不是别人
Have you ever been in a tornado? No.
你见过龙卷风吗   没有
What else do you have?
你还经历过什么？
Um, earthquakes?
呃  地震？
Really? No.
真的？ 假的
I dream sometimes about flying.
我曾经做过一个梦 我在飞
It starts out like I'm running really, really fast.
开始的时候我只是跑，那么快
I'm, like, superhuman.
我就像 超人
And the terrain starts to get really rocky and steep.
渐渐地面变成了陡峭的岩石
And then I'm running so fast that my feet aren't even touching the ground.
我跑的太快了  离开了地面
And I'm floating, and it's like this amazing, amazing realness.
我飞起来了  很奇妙  奇妙且真实
I'm free. I'm safe.
感觉很自由  很安全
Then I realize,l'm completely alone.
然后我明白了 我是一个人
And then I wake up.
然后就醒了
As he listened, Tom began to realize...
他听着 汤姆开始发觉...
These weren't stories routinely told.
这并不是随便讲给人听的故事
These were stories one had to earn.
而是有资格的人才能听的
He could feel the wall coming down.
他感觉到那堵墙正在消失
He wondered if anyone else had made it this far.
他很好奇有没有其他人也曾到这里
Which is why the next six words changed everything.
而后面的话  改变了一切
I've never told anybody that before.
我以前从没跟别人讲过这些
I guess I'm not just anybody.
我猜我不是 别人
So what are you exactly?
那你现在是什么？
What, like, are we going steady? Come on.
就像  你们恋爱了吗？  拜托
You know, we're... we're adults. We know how we feel.
你知道的...我们... 我们是成年人   你知道我们在想什么
We don't need to put labels on it.
我们不用贴那些标签
I mean, "boyfriend," "girlfriend."
我是说"男朋友"  "女朋友"
All that stuff is... It's really juvenile.
那些东西都... 太幼稚了
You sound gay. You really do.
听起来好像你是同性恋  确实
And you， you've been with Robyn since 1998?
而你  你和瑞比从1998 年开始的吧？
I don't think the two of you are exactly authorities on modern relationships.
我觉得你们俩不是  现代爱情方面的专家
So, what should I do? You should ask her.
那我该怎么办？ 你该去问她
What?
怎么了？
Well, why rock the boat, is what I'm thinking.
我在想  干吗要自找麻烦
I mean, things are going well.
一切不都很好吗
You start putting labels on it, that's like the kiss of death.
你想确定关系  但那可能就完蛋了
It's like saying, "I love you."
就像在说 " 我爱你 "
That's what happened between me and Sean.
我和肖恩也是那样
I'm saying you do want to ask her.
我是说你确实想问她
It's obvious. You're just afraid you'll get an answer you don't want,
很明显   你只是怕答案不是你想要的
Wait! No. We're not done here.
等等  不  我们不能这样结束
Look, it's easy, Tom.
这很容易 Tom
Just don't be a pussy.
别跟个小姑娘似的
You okay?
你还好吧？
Yeah. You sure?
恩   是吗？
Summer, I gotta ask you something.
Summer  我得问你点事
What?
什么？
What are we doing?
我们在干嘛？
I don't know.
我不知道
Who cares?
有什么关系？
I'm happy. Aren't you happy? Yeah.
我很开心 你不也是吗 ？  是的
Good.
对啊
London, 1964.
伦敦 1964
Those girls knew how to dress.
那些女孩知道怎么打扮
Nowadays, it's all these sunglasses and tattoos.
可今天  到处都是墨镜和纹身
It's handbags with little dogs in them.
手提包里放着小狗
Who okayed this? Some people like it.
谁允许的？ 有人喜欢
I like how you dress.
我喜欢你的打扮
I was thinking about getting a butterfly tattoo about yea big on my ankle.
我考虑过 在我脚上刺个蝴蝶
No.
别
Oh.
哦
How's it going?
怎么样
Uh, okay.
嗯 还行
You live around here?
你住附近？
Um, yeah, not too far.
对 不是很远
I've never seen you here before.
我从来没过你
You're not too observant.
你不是很善于观察
That's funny. You're funny.
很好笑  你很幽默
So let me buy you a drink. No, thank you.
请你喝一杯 算了 谢谢
You with this guy? Hey, I'm Tom.
你在和他约会？   嗨 我叫汤姆
Whatever. So, come on. One drink. What are you drinking?
随便  来吧  请你喝一杯   你喝什么？
I said no, thanks.
我说了算了  谢谢
You're serious? This guy?
你还挺认真？这小子？
I'm flattered, but I'm not interested.
我受宠若惊   但我没兴趣
So why don't you go over there and leave us alone? Thanks.
那你为什么离我们远点？   谢谢你了
It's a free country.
这是自由的国家
I can't believe this is your boyfriend.
不敢相信他是你男朋友
What are you doing?
你干嘛？
It was really just a crazy thing.
这真疯狂
Hey, what's the matter?
嗨  你怎么了？
I just...  I can't believe you.
我只是...我无法相信你
You can't believe me?
你无法相信我？
You were so completely, completely uncool in there.
你很 非常 不冷静
Wait. Are you mad at me? I just got my ass kicked for you.
等等  你生我气了？   我为你挨打
Oh, really? Was that for me? Was that for my benefit?
是吗？  是为我吗  为了我的好处？
Yes, it was.
是的
Okay, well, next time don't, 'cause I don't need your help.
好吧  那下次别这样做  我不需要你帮忙
You know what? I'm really tired.
你知道吗？  我很累
Can we talk about this tomorrow?
我们能明天再谈吗？
No. You know what?
不  你知道什么？
I'm not going anywhere till you tell me what's going on.
我哪都不去  除非你告诉我怎么了
Nothing's going on.
没什么
We're just...
我们只是...
What? We're just what?
什么？  我们只是什么？
We're just friends.
我们只是朋友
Don't even try to.
想都别想
This is not how you treat your friend.
你不是这样对你朋友的
Kissing in the copy room?
在打印室里接吻？
Come on! Friends, my balls!
算了吧！  朋友  真是蛋疼！
I like you, Tom. I just don't want a relationship
我喜欢你 汤姆 我只是不想恋爱
you're not the only one that gets a say in this!
你不是唯一有发言权的！
I do too! And I say we're a couple
我也有！  我说 我们是一对
After you, please.
先请
I shouldn't have done that.
我不该那样
Done what? Gotten mad at you.
不该什么?  生你的气
I'm sorry.
对不起
Look, we don't have to put a label on it.
好吧  我们不需要贴上标签
That's fine. I get it.
这很好  我明白了
But, you know, I just...I need some consistency.
但你知道  我只是... 需要一点一致性
I know.
我知道
I need to know that you're not gonna wake up in the morning...and... feel differently.
我只是想弄清楚  你不会一天早上醒来...感觉... 不一样
And I can't give you that.
我不能给你保证
Nobody can.
没人能
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
No, it doesn't hurt.
没事
I like you.
我喜欢你
All right.
没事了
Shh. Well, what about you? Did you ever even have a boyfriend?
那么  你呢？  有过男朋友吗？
Well, of course. Yeah?
当然  嗯？
Yeah. Well, tell me about them.
恩  跟我讲讲他们
No. Why not?
不  为什么？
Because it's not important.
因为那不重要
I'm interested.
我想听
All right. Fine.
好吧
Yeah. I can take it. Fine.
我能接受
No. He was a rower.
不 他是个赛艇运动员
He was very hot.
他很性感
That's the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
这是我听过的 最白痴的事
No, it's not. It's awesome. Trust me.
肯定不是  那很了不起   相信我
I'm serious.
我说真的
I'll go first.
我先来
You having fun? Yeah.
很好玩？对
This is the kind of thing you did with The Puma, isn't it?
你和美洲狮也玩这个？
Oh, we rarely left the room.
不 我们很少出门
Penis!
鸡巴
She has it too. Penis! Penis!
她也是    鸡巴！   鸡巴！
Shh. Everyone's looking over here. I'm done. I'm done.
小声点  人们都在看你  好了 好了
You're done? Yeah.
真的？   恩
This is too much. Unleash me. I'm done.
太过分了  放开我吧 我不喊了
Promise? I promise.
保证？  - 保证
I promise.
我保证
Penis!
鸡巴！
It's very complex. Mmm.
很复杂  恩
Do you want to go to the movies? Yep.
想去看电影吗？ 恩
Mr. Vance would like to see you in his office.
万斯先生要你去他办公室见他
Have a seat.
坐吧
Has something happened to you recently?
你最近怎么了？
What do you mean?
什么意思？
No.
没有
Look, I don't mean to pry, but...
我并不是在刺探你  可......
Does this have something to do with Summer leaving?
和莎莫的离开有关吗
Who? My assistant.
谁？   我的助理
Never mind.
没关系
The reason I'm asking is, lately your work performance...has been... a little off.
我找你来  是因为你的业绩...有点... 下滑
Um, here's something that you wrote last week.
呃... 这些是你上周写的
Uh...  "Roses are red, violets are blue.Fuck you, whore."
恩..." 玫瑰是红色的  紫罗兰是蓝色 去你的 婊子 "
Mr. Vance, are you firing me? No. No.
万斯先生 你要解雇我吗？  不  不
Relax, Hansen. You're one of the good ones.
放松点 Hansen  你是我见过的最好的一个
Okay. Uh, yeah, I'm sorry.
恩  呃  抱歉
Things have been a little difficult.
有点复杂
That's okay. I completely understand that.
没事  我很清楚这一切
Uh...  Good. Okay.
呃... 很好
Now back to work you go.
继续工作吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Hey. Hey.
嗨  嗨
Don't you have 20 cards to write by Friday? Nope. All done.
你不是周五前要写20张卡片吗？ 不，全写完了
Really? Can you help me? 'Cause I've run out of ways to say "congrats."
真的？ 能帮帮我吗？  我已经用尽那些 " 恭喜 " 了
Okay. I got "Good job," "Well done" and "Way to go."
好的 我有 " 不错 "  " 好样的 "  " 干得好 "
That's it.
就这些了
How about "Every day you make me proud,but today you get a card."
" 你每天都让我感到骄傲，但今天你得到一张卡片 " 这个怎么样
Shit, that's good! I know.
操  真棒！  我知道
Have you tried "Merry"?
" 欢乐"  怎么样？
Wow! That's perfect! Merry! Wow!
哇！  太棒了！ 欢乐！  哇 ！
We've been stuck on this for an hour.
我们困在这一个小时了
Hmm...
恩...
"I love us"?
" 我爱我们 "？
Aw.
哇
I hate Summer.
我恨莎莫
I hate her crooked teeth.
恨她的歪曲的牙齿
I hate her 1960s haircut.
恨她60年代的发型
I hate her knobby knees.
恨她凹凸的膝盖
And I hate her cockroach-shaped splotch on her neck.
恨她脖子上蟑螂似的污点
I hate the way she smacks her lips before she talks.
恨她说话前先舔下嘴唇
And I hate the way she sounds when she laughs.
我恨她的笑
I hate this song!
我恨这首歌！
Son, you're gonna have to exit the vehicle.
孩子  你还是下车吧
I normally don't do blind dates
我通常不会相亲
But Paul and Robyn spoke very highly of you.
但保罗和罗宾对你赞不绝口
Ah. They said you write greeting cards.
哦  他们说你写贺卡
That's so interesting. I wanted to write.
太有趣了  我也想写
I actually majored in English in college,
我大学是学英语的
but what are you gonna do with that degree?
但你出来又能干嘛?
I went to Brown. Where did you go? Alison.
我去了布朗  你去过哪 ?  埃里森
Hmm?
恩?
Listen, it's great to meet you,
听着 能认识你很高兴
and... you're a very attractive girl.
恩... 你是个很有魅力的女孩
It's not gonna go anywhere. Oh.
这样不会有什么结果
She took a giant shit on my face.
她却扔我脸上坨屎
Not literally. That's disgusting. Jesus.
假的   天哪 真扯淡
What's the matter with you?
你怎么了？
The point is,I'm messed up. I am.
重点是我纠结了  真的
You know, on the one hand, I want to forget her.
一方面  我想忘了她
On the other hand,I know that she's the only person in the entire universe that will make me happy.
但另一方面 我知道她是整个宇宙  唯一能让我快乐的人
You ever do this?
你曾经这样过吗？
There's two options really.
有两种解释
Either... she's an evil,emotionless, miserable human being,or... she's a robot.
一个是 ... 她邪恶 没人性  卑鄙 或者...她是个机器人
Small Wonder. You know, Vicki.
《机器娃娃》里的薇姬
That would explain a lot actually. Can I ask you a question?
这样实际上一切都能解释了  我能问你个问题吗？
Yeah. She never cheated on you?
好的 她从未劈过腿吗？
No. Never. She ever take advantage of you in any way?
没有 她利用你了吗？
No.
没有
And she told you up front that she didn't want a boyfriend.
她之前说她不想要男朋友  对吧
Yeah.
对
I got a great idea.
我明白了
Waste of time. You don't look anything like Summer.
浪费时间  你跟莎莫差太远了
Now departing on Track 2, Pacific Surfliner.
太平洋滑浪线二车道即将出发
Full service to Santa Barbara.
终点站是圣巴巴拉
All aboard, please.
请您马上登车
Hey, baby. Hey, you here?
嘿 小子 嘿 你在这儿？
No, man. It's gonna be all old people.
哥们  那全是老人
Yeah, but you said you were going. That's why I'm going.
对  是你说你要去  我才来的
And that's why I called her last night, telling her I was sick.
所以昨晚给她打电话  说我病了
Maybe you'll meet some hot granddaughters or something.
也许你能碰见个  性感小萝莉什么的
I'm hanging up now. Bye, baby.
我挂了  再见 哥们
May I have your attention, please
各位旅客请注意
Hi, Tom!
嗨  汤姆！
Hey. Summer.
嗨  莎莫
Are you going to Millie's?
你是要去米莉家么
Me too. Cool.
我也是  太好了
I forgot you knew her. Yeah, we worked together all that time, so-
我忘了你认识她    恩  我们一起工作...
of course. I love Millie. She's the sweetest.
当然  我喜欢米莉  她很可爱
She is.
嗯
How are you?  I'm good.
你怎么样？    不错
Good. I wrote to you. I never heard back
恩  我给你写信  没收到过你的回信
It got kind of crazy, and the holidays came up, so work was...
这些天过得一团糟  这放假了也不得休息  工作...
You still working for Vance?
你还在万斯那儿干？
Yeah.
对
"The Architecture of Happiness."
" 幸福建筑 "
Yeah. That looks like a good book.
看起来很不错
Yeah...
恩 ...
Yeah, let's get coffee.
走吧  喝杯咖啡
After you.
你先
You look nice. Thanks.
你看起来很精神  谢谢
So do you.
你也是
No.
不
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
现在我宣布你们结为夫妻
You may kiss the bride.
你可以吻新娘了
Well, you snore. No, I don't.
嗯 你打呼噜   没有
You do. No, I don't.
当然有  不，我没有
Yeah. Well, you do too.
好吧   你也打过
Oh, I definitely do. And your feet reek.
噢 当然    你脚还臭
That one time! No, every time.
就一次！   不，每次都是
That one time! No.
就那一次好吧！不
That one time especially, but every time.
每次都是  那一次格外臭
It's ridiculous. You're ridiculous.
真荒唐  你真荒唐
Your favorite Beatle is Ringo.
披头士里你最爱林戈
Damn right!
太对了！
Ringo's the best.
林戈最棒
You got me.
你抓到我了
Duck.
鸭子
Wanna dance? Yeah.
跳支舞吧？好的
Okay.
好吧
I was gonna maybe have a party on Friday
周五我可能要开个派对
Do you want to come?
你想来吗？
Yeah.
好吧
If you're not busy.
如果你不忙
I don't think I will be.
应该不会
They're good, huh? They are good.
很不错 对吧？很棒
I guess I just got lucky.
我想我人品爆发了
we met in elementary school.
我们从小学就认识了
In seventh grade we had the same class schedule
七年级时我们课表都一样
we just clicked
我们很合拍
Love?
爱情？
Shit, I don't know.
该死  我可不太懂
As long as she's cute and she's willing, right?
只要她愿意  又可爱  对吧？
I'm flexible on the cute
其实可不可爱也无所谓
She's the light that guides me home.
她是指引我回家的明灯
Yes, that is from one of our cards.
好吧  没错  是我引用贺卡上的话
No. Someone else wrote it.
不  别人写的
Doesn't make it less true.
但说的很对
Robyn's better than the girl of my dreams.
罗宾比我的梦中女孩还要好
She's real.
她真实
Tom walked to her apartment,intoxicated by the promise of the evening.
汤姆去了她的公寓 沉醉在那晚的约定中
He believed that this time his expectations would align with reality.
他相信这次期待会与现实并行
Hi. Hey.
嗨  嘿
I like your tie.
我喜欢你的领带
How you doing? Good. How are you?
最近好吗？ 很好  你呢？
Good.
不错
I brought you something.
这个是送你的
That's so nice.
真漂亮
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you so much.
太谢谢你了
I'm excited to read it.
我都迫不及待想读了
Tom, what is it that you do?  Uh, I write greeting cards.
汤姆 你做什么工作的？ 我为贺卡撰写贺词
Tom could be a really great architect if he wanted to be.
如果汤姆愿意  他会是个很棒的建筑师
That's unusual.
真奇怪
what?
什么？
Do you guys know each other?
你们认识吗？
Get a room!
去开房吧！
I've been calling you every five minutes. Are you okay?
我每5分钟给你打次电话  你没事吧？
I'm great. What happened to you?
我很好  你怎么了？
I don't wanna talk about it.
我不想谈这个
Where are we going? It's Thursday!
去哪？   今天是周四！
This one says, "Go for it!"
这个人说 " 加油! "
And this one says, "You can do it!"
这个说 " 你能做到! "
We have a whole line of inspirational photographic cards featuring Pickles, my cat.
我们有一系列富有灵感的照片贺卡,描绘了我的小猫 " 泡菜 "
I think people will really enjoy them.
人们肯定会很喜欢
Thank you. Good job.
谢谢  干得不错
That's inspirational stuff.
挺有创意的
Okay. Who's next?
好的  下一个是谁？
We haven't heard from Sympathy in a while.
好长时间没有慰问组的消息了
The Winter Collection? Do you have anything to contribute?
冬日收藏系列？  你有什么贡献么？
Uh, no.
额 没有
I really don't.
真没有
Okay.
好吧
We'll come back to you. Uh, McKenzie?
过会再叫你   嗯 麦肯齐？
Can I say something about the cat? Well, okay.
关于那只猫我能说两句吗？ 嗯 好的
Tom! "Go for it" and "You can do it"?
汤姆！   " 加油 " 和 " 你能做到 "？
That's not inspirational. That's suicidal.
那不是创意  那是自杀
If Pickles goes for it right there, that's a dead cat.
如果 " 泡菜 " 真的去寻找了  它就成死猫了
These are lies. We're liars.
这些是骗人的  我们都是骗子
Think about it. Why do people buy these things?
想想吧   为什么人们买这些？
It's not 'cause they want to say how they feel.
不是因为他们想说这些
People buy cards 'cause they can't say how they feel, or they're afraid to.
人们买贺卡  是因为他们不能或不敢  说出他们想说的
We provide the service that lets them off the hook.
我们提供服务  好让他们摆脱这些
You know what? Let's level with America.
知道吗？  让我们对美国人说实话吧
At least let them speak for themselves! Right?
起码让他们亲口说话！对吗？
Look! What is this? What does it say?
看看！  这些都是什么？  写的什么？
"Congratulations on your new baby." Right?
" 恭喜你喜得贵子 "   是吗?
How about this one, with all the pretty hearts on the front? I know where this is going.
这个呢  这个有爱心封面的  我知道里面是什么
"Happy Valentine's Day, sweetheart. I love you."
" 情人节快乐  甜心  我爱你 "
That sweet? Ain't love grand?
真甜蜜？  爱情多伟大？
This is exactly what I'm talking about.
这就是我想说的
What does that even mean?
它到底是什么？
Do you know?
你知道吗？
If somebody gave me this card, Mr. Vance, I would eat it.
如果谁给我这样的卡片  万斯先生  我就吃了它
It's these cards, and the movies, and the pop songs
就是这些卡片  电影  流行歌曲
They're to blame for all the lies.
它们该对所有的谎言负责
and the heartache, everything.
心痛  和所有的一切
And we're responsible. I'm responsible.
我们也有责任  我也有责任
I think we do a bad thing here.
我认为我们在做错事
People should be able to say how they feel,how they really feel
人们说出他们的感受  他们真实的感受
Sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起  抱歉
I quit.
我辞职
There's enough bullshit in the world without my help.
这世界已经够扯蛋了  不需要我了
All right. Next we do running drills.
好了  下次我们做跑步练习
Hey, you're sketching again.
嗨  你又在描了
Okay, Tom. We got 20 seconds. Talk to me. You okay?
好的 汤姆  我们有20秒  和我谈谈   没事吧?
Yeah, I'm good.
没事  我很好
You know, my friends are all in love with you.
你知道 我那些朋友们都很喜欢你
Plenty of other fish in the sea. Thanks.
海里还有很多鱼  谢谢
Those are guppies.
那些是食人鱼
Yeah.
对
Hey, Tom? Mmm.
嘿 汤姆？  嗯
Look, I know you think that she was the one,but I don't.
我知道你你认为  她就是你的命中注定，但我不觉得
Now, I think you're just remembering the good stuff.
你只记得那些好的那一面
Next time you look back...
下次  当你回首往事的时候...
I really think you should look again.
我真觉得你该好好想想了
It's playing at 5:00. Do you wanna see it?
5点开始  你想去看吗？
No, I really want to see it. Let's go.
不 我想去看  走吧
You okay? Yeah.
你没事吧？ 没事
what is it? The movie?
怎么了？  电影？
It's nothing. I'm just being stupid.
没事 我只是太傻了
Yeah? Yeah.
是吗？恩
It pains me we live in a world where nobody's heard of Spearmint.
没人听说过留兰香的世界真让人痛心
I've never heard of them.
我就没听说过他们
They're track one.
它们是第一首
Oh, yeah.
哦  对
So, what do you wanna do?
那么  接下来干嘛？
I think I'm just gonna call it a day.
我想我该走了
You don't wanna get some dinner? Are you hungry?
不想一块吃晚饭吗？   你不饿吗？
You all right?
你没事吧？
I'm just tired. Okay.
我只是有点累了  好吧
I got it. Pancakes!
我有个好主意   薄烤饼！
Hey, Tom.
嗨 汤姆
I thought I might see you here.
我想也许能在这见到你
I always loved this place, ever since you brought me.
你带我来过后  我就爱上这里了
I guess I should say congratulations.
我是不是该说  恭喜了
Only if you mean it.
除非你真心诚意
Well, in that case...
好吧  既然这样...
So, are you okay?
那么，最近怎么样？
I will be, eventually.
总会好起来的
I like your suit. Ah, thanks.
这件衣服真不错 啊 谢谢
You look sharp.
看起来很精神
So do you. Thanks.
你也是     谢谢
I quit the office. You did?
我辞职了     真的吗？
I didn't know. That's great!
我都不知道  真棒！
you're married.
你结婚了
Yeah. It's crazy, huh?
是的 很难以置信  对吧？
So why'd you dance with me?
那你为什么还要跟我跳舞
'Cause I wanted to.
因为我想
You just do what you want, don't you?
你只是做你想做的  是吗？
You never wanted to be anybody's girlfriend,
你从来不想做谁的女朋友
But now you're somebody's wife.
而你现在却是谁的妻子
I don't think I'll ever understand that.
我可能永远都理解不了
I mean, it doesn't make sense.
我是说  这不合情理
It just happened.
可事实就是这样
Right, but that's what I don't understand. What just happened?
对  可这就是我理解不了的   什么发生了？
I just woke up one day, and I knew.
我只是一觉醒来   然后就明白了
Knew what?
明白什么？
What I was never sure of with you.
和你在一起时  我一直不能确定的
Realizing that everything you believe in is complete and utter bullshit.
当你发现你的信仰全是狗屎的时候
It sucks.
真糟
I should have listened to you.
我应该听你的
What? What are you smiling at?
什么？  你笑什么？
Tom. What?
汤姆 什么？
What are you looking at me like that for?
你这样看着我干嘛？
Well, you know,
那些，你懂的，
I guess it's 'cause...
我觉得...
I was sitting in a deli and reading Dorian Gray
我坐在店里看 道林·格雷
and... a guy comes up to me...and asked me about it,
然后...一个人走过来...问我那本书怎么样
And... now he's my husband.
现在...他是我的丈夫
Yeah. And... so?
是啊 那 然后呢?
So, what if I'd gone to the movies?
那么 如果我去看电影了呢？
What if I had gone somewhere else for lunch?
或者我去别处吃午饭？
What if I'd gotten there 10 minutes later?
要么晚去了那10分钟呢？
It was meant to be.
那是注定好的
And I just kept thinking,
然后我就不停的想
Tom was right. No.
汤姆是对的    不
It just wasn't me that you were right about.
只是你的那个人不是我
I should go.
我该走了
But I'm really happy to see that you're doing well.
但看到你过的不错  我真的很高兴
Summer!
莎莫！
I really do hope that you're happy.
祝你幸福
Most days of the year are unremarkable.
一年中的很多天都是很平凡的
They begin and they end...with no lasting memories made in between.
它们开始 和结束...没有留下任何回忆
Most days have no impact...on the course of a life.
在一生中大多数日子对生活没什么影响
May 23 was a Wednesday.
五月二十三日是 一个星期三
Are you interviewing? Sorry?
你是来面试的吗？什么？
Are you interviewing for the position?
你是来面试这个职位的吗？
Mm-hmm.
嗯
My competition.
我的竞争者
It would appear.
看来是的
Yeah. So, a little awkward.
是啊 那么 有点尴尬
Yeah.
对
Well, I hope you, um, don't get the job.
那么 我祝你  嗯 祝你面试失败
Well, I hope you don't get the job.
那我也祝你 面试失败
Have I seen you before?
我以前见过你吗？
Me? I don't think so.
我？应该没有
Do you ever go to Angelus Plaza?
你去过祈祷广场吗？
Yes. That's, like, my favorite spot in the city.
当然 那大概是我在这座城市里最喜欢的地方
Yeah. Except for the parking lots
是的 除了那些停车场
Yeah.  I agree. Yeah, yeah.
是的 我同意   对 对
I think I've seen you there. Really?
我想我见过你   真的？
Yeah. I haven't seen you.
是啊 我没见过你
You must not have been looking.
你一定是在看其他什么
Coincidence. That's all anything ever is.
巧合  每时每刻都在发生
Nothing more than coincidence.
仅仅是巧合
Come on back. Thank you.
该你了 谢谢
Tom had finally learned there are no miracles.
汤姆终于明白了  没有奇迹
There's no such thing as fate.
没有那么多命运
Nothing is meant to be.
没什么注定的
He knew. He was sure of it now.
他懂了  很确定
He was pretty sure.
他很确信
Hey.You again.
嘿  又是你
Yeah. I, uh, was just wondering...
是的 我 嗯 只是在想...
if maybe after this, if, um, you...
也许在面试过后... 你...
you want to get some coffee or something.
是否可以一起去喝咖啡什么的
Oh, I'm sorry.
噢 抱歉
I'm sort of supposed to meet someone after this.
结束后我可能要见一个人
Okay.
好吧
Sure.
好的
Okay. Well, then I'll, uh... I'll wait for you
好 那我 嗯... 我等你
We'll figure it out. We'll figure it out.
我们再商量吧    我们再商量
My name's Tom. Nice to meet you. I'm Autumn.
我是汤姆   很高兴认识你 我是奥特姆